<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Minimalist blog.</description>
    <link>https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:10:37 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:10:37 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Symposium, Book👏review👏</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I read the whole book and I liked it, but I felt like I needed something more logic-based after I finished reading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;random-note&quot;&gt;Random note&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was surprised how bisexual everyone was. When some of them talked about the concept of love, they were talking about the homosexual relationship between an older and a younger man.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One person even said that love of boys is a more noble kind of love because they are born smarter and overall better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-on-the-actual-point-of-the-book&quot;&gt;Notes on the actual point of the book:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every speaker took a turn and shared their take on Eros with others, here are some points they made that I still remember:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is an upper and a lower kind of love
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;lower love is the love of things that change: money, appearance, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;upper love is the love of the truth, which doesn’t change&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When people do things for love, even the most atypical kind of behavior suddenly becomes acceptable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One speaker had a theory that people originally had 2 heads, arms, legs .. and that they were split into two and now we search the world for our soulmate from whom we were separated like this&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Socrates said that people wish for things that they don’t possess, which he very clearly explains and it makes sense. But then he transfers that principle onto love without any explanation and claims that, therefore, love things that they don’t have. I didn’t see why that should be the case when I was reading the book, but it made more sense when I heard that ancient greek had the same word for love and want.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The idea that lovers should make each other the best person they can be also appeared in this book and I like it a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/2019/Symposium,-book-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/2019/Symposium,-book-review/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ai Superpowers, Book👏review👏</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;random-notes-on-a-book-by-kai-fu-lee&quot;&gt;Random notes on a book by Kai-fu Lee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its the first book on AI I ever read. Unfortunately, I stopped in about 3/4 of the book, I felt like it was getting repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I liked the authors’ notes on China, it’s a topic I’m very interested in. Here are some thoughts that I haven’t heard before:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mobile apps are done differently in western countries - many apps for many different things instead of one big one for everything.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Western companies routinely fail when investing money and resources into the Chinese market - they don’t adapt to different needs and habits of the Chinese.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Chinese companies that rip off western brands (in the internet sphere) are not just lazy copycats, they are willing to adapt their product which makes them win out over the original.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Chinas’ copycats competing against each other gave birth to great Chinese entrepreneurs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And some notes on AIs’ future (and China again):
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The age of implementation arrived and AI research might slow down.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The amount and quality of data will be a big factor and China has a centralized mobile application (WeChat) that produces enormous amounts of data, and that also reaches much further into the real life of its’ own users more than any other western app.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I never realized how much of the current AI is just on the internet and not in real life.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some topics from the latter part of the book:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The potential loss of jobs and existential crisis.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;These topics seemed quite theoretical and were relying on a lot of what-ifs, so decided to skip them. Might revisit them later.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/2019/AI-Superpowers,-book-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/2019/AI-Superpowers,-book-review/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Try Stopping Early</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re a competitive person, then you like spending your time effectively.
The natural time spent distribution of any sort of endeavor looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/time_graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;The typical distribution of your interest and time spent&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An old Czech proverb says that you should “end at the height of things”. It’s not something many people do, simply because their interest still brings them pleasure and they don’t want to or don’t have the will power, to end things abruptly. Quite often you see people who stopped giving their fullest to a sport, yet they still hang around for a few years, missing workouts here and there and seemingly just doing everything out of habit, with no real goal in mind. Or people who are now adults and still come back to videogames, but always ever less so often than before, until they eventually stop altogether. Or people who still hang on to their old partners, even though they know that their relationship is dying down and won’t stand the test of time in the ensuing few years. If you feel like you’re reaching the right slope of the graph, man up, overcome nostalgia and completely cut it out of your life and you’ll be rewarded by only remembering the good times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/2019/Try-stopping-early/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/2019/Try-stopping-early/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Overcomming Procrastination</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The key is in setting a specific goal. If you wish to be wealthy, then that’s a great start to becoming wealthy, but it’s not a great goal. &lt;strong&gt;Great goals should make you do things to achieve them&lt;/strong&gt;. When wishing to be wealthy, a great goal would be to, for example, launch a startup. It’s quite simple to see what things a startup CEO should know/do. They should study basic economics, follow current trends, learn how to be likable, read relevant books, etc.. And since you already have these things in your head, you’ll be inclined to pick a few that you like and start studying. It comes down to being able to see the specific things that you’re missing and you’ll automatically start filling the gaps to get closer to your goal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/2019/Overcomming-procrastination/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jaroslavurbann.github.io/blog/2019/Overcomming-procrastination/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
